<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Group Project details | Multiple Regression</title>
    <link>/group/</link>
      <atom:link href="/group/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Group Project details</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <image>
      <url>/img/social-image.png</url>
      <title>Group Project details</title>
      <link>/group/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPUMS Extract &amp; Analysis Plan</title>
      <link>/group/05-group-dataextractandanalysisplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/group/05-group-dataextractandanalysisplan/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#content-of-the-document&#34;&gt;Content of the Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#data-extract-what-variables-and-samples-you-plan-to-request-from-ipums&#34;&gt;Data Extract: What Variables and Samples you Plan to Request from IPUMS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#analysis-plan-what-do-you-plan-to-do-with-the-data-once-you-have-it-from-ipums&#34;&gt;Analysis Plan: What do you plan to do with the data once you have it from IPUMS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submit this as a pdf to moodle. The pdf doesn’t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to be made R - you can make it in Google Docs or Word, just saved as a pdf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should essentially add this additional material to your final group proposal. You can either add this at the end or integreate it where appropriate (i.e., when talking about a specific variable).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;content-of-the-document&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Content of the Document&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;data-extract-what-variables-and-samples-you-plan-to-request-from-ipums&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Data Extract: What Variables and Samples you Plan to Request from IPUMS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be a list of the exact variables - by their variable name in the IPUMS system - you plan to include in a data extract request and the “sample”, or which time period(s) you are including.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;analysis-plan-what-do-you-plan-to-do-with-the-data-once-you-have-it-from-ipums&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analysis Plan: What do you plan to do with the data once you have it from IPUMS?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This information should include a very clear list of steps or of the process that you expect to undertake to do any necessary data management/wrangling to get the variables in the format you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should specify the steps you plan to take – not to actually take them yet, just thinking through the plan – to investigate the distributions of the variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should have written out the regression models – in equation notation – with all of the variables as they will be included, and (re-)stated which coefficients of the model reflect your the hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last point should make really clear whether you are including variables as a factor (see the suggested HW4 question) or multiple indicator variables, and in either case which level will be the reference group. You will need to spell out the hypothetical regression model with each and every beta estimate that you plan to include.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this does not expect that you have done any of this work yet with your data or in R. It is simply an exercise to get you thinking about what exactly you will need to do next – this keeps you organized and in many cases is an additional opportunity to explicate your thinking about your topic since this is getting even a little closer to actually testing your hypotheses. And for those of you newer to &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;, it will help articulate where you may want to get additional help for this kind of work (plan to come to the &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt; workshop on Friday 3/27, 2-4pm!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; assignment will be a data appendix, where you will illustrate that you have the data in hand and have brought it into R, what of the steps you list above that you have been able to complete and what you have left to do, what unanticipated issues have arisen, and what this exploratory data analysis (not yet having fit a model, just exploring the variables one at a time and with scatterplots and other visuals) is telling you about your main research question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do I Get the IPUMS Data</title>
      <link>/group/04-group-ipums-gettingdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/group/04-group-ipums-gettingdata/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-data-do-you-want&#34;&gt;What data do you want?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-do-you-get-the-data-from-ipums&#34;&gt;How do you get the data &lt;em&gt;from IPUMS&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-do-you-get-the-data-into-rstudio&#34;&gt;How do you get the data &lt;em&gt;into RStudio&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting data from IPUMS is very easy – that’s part of why we use it in this class for projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-data-do-you-want&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What data do you want?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a variety of ways to have identified what you need, but the gist is that you can browse through how the variables are organized, use an A-Z index, or a search through the variable names and descriptions. Hopefully by this point in the group project process, the variable identification process is more or less complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;how-do-you-get-the-data-from-ipums&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How do you get the data &lt;em&gt;from IPUMS&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good analogy of the IPUMS website interface is online shopping: you’re working to identify the variables you want, you put them in your cart, select which years/samples you want, and then submit the extract (i.e., “checking out” or “buying” what’s in your cart).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;how-do-you-get-the-data-into-rstudio&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How do you get the data &lt;em&gt;into RStudio&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your data extract has been processed, you need to download two files - a data file and a codebook - and then use the &lt;code&gt;ipumsr&lt;/code&gt; package to bring those data into R/RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;ipumsr&lt;/code&gt; package has &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ipumsr/vignettes/ipums.html&#34;&gt;helpful vignettes&lt;/a&gt; that introduces this process and has helpful screen shots of what you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a video I made walking through these steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/z9JSYh4jBCQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft Proposal</title>
      <link>/group/02-group-draftproposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/group/02-group-draftproposal/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#content-of-the-proposal&#34;&gt;Content of the Proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#group-members-name&#34;&gt;Group Members / Name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#purpose&#34;&gt;Purpose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#population&#34;&gt;Population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#response-variable&#34;&gt;Response Variable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#explanatory-variables&#34;&gt;Explanatory Variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#going-from-draft-into-final-proposal&#34;&gt;Going from Draft into Final Proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial and revised proposals should ideally be the same structure/content, with the draft being less complete or with a few different ideas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the initial, draft proposal, many of the specifics may be sketchy still. That’s fine, and part of why we have a draft to get you thinking about this and give us a chance to work together to figure out what makes most sense. If you’re stuck on the idea phase, just list a bunch of the ideas you’re thinking about and which of the IPUMS data sets looks most relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submit this as a pdf to moodle. The pdf doesn’t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to be made R - you can make it in Google Docs or Word, just saved as a pdf - especially for the draft, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://sds291.netlify.com/group/02-modelfinalgroupproposal.rmd&#34;&gt;here is an &lt;code&gt;.RMD&lt;/code&gt; file for the Model Group Draft Proposal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;content-of-the-proposal&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Content of the Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;group-members-name&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Group Members / Name&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List the members of your group and your group name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;title&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposed title of your project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;purpose&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the general topic/phenomenon you want to study, as well some focused questions that you hope to answer and specific hypotheses that you intend to assess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;data&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the data that you plan to use, with specifications of where it can be found (URL) and a short description. Which IPUMS surveys, in which years? Describe the source of the data - was it a survey, and if so, how were people selected and how was the data collected - in a few sentences. You can look to the IPUMS descriptions for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;population&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Population&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specify what the observational units are (i.e. the rows of the data frame), describe the larger population/phenomenon to which you’ll try to generalize, and (if appropriate) estimate roughly how many such individuals there are in the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;response-variable&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Response Variable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the response variable? What are its units? Estimate the range of possible values that it may take on. [&lt;em&gt;Most projects will use a quantitative or a binary response variable (we will cover logistic regression for binary outcomes after Spring Break and in enough time that you can complete the project)&lt;/em&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;explanatory-variables&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Explanatory Variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should have one, primary explanatory variable that is your main hypothesis. You may have other explanatory variables associated with secondary hypotheses (no more than 2 secondary hypotheses, or three hypotheses total).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you will also have explanatory variables that you want to control for – variables that may be associated with your primary explanatory and your response variables that you want to include in your multiple regression model to adjust your main association for those competing explanations. Demographics (age, sex, race) and socioeconomic status are common ones for individual-level survey data. Your final regression model must include at least 5 confounding variables beyond your main explanatory variable that is included in your hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carefully define each variable and describe how each was measured (self-report/direct observation). For categorical variables, list the possible categories; for quantitative variables, specify the units of measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;going-from-draft-into-final-proposal&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Going from Draft into Final Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I respond to your initial proposal (within a week or so of submitting), you will revise it (perhaps starting with a different dataset), then submit a new proposal that addresses our feedback. Note that you may well need to start from scratch, so be thoughtful but open during the drafting process, and know that there will need to be revision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Final Proposal should include essentially the same information required as the initial proposal, but with more detail on the rationale for the study (i.e., why does this question matter? what is its relevance outside of this class?), revised hypotheses, and clearer proposed methods to test those hypotheses. See the Model Group Draft Proposal for an example of a fully fleshed out, comprehensive example of a final proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can I do with IPUMS Data?</title>
      <link>/group/04-group-ipums-whatisipums/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/group/04-group-ipums-whatisipums/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#why-are-we-using-ipums-for-this-class&#34;&gt;Why are we using IPUMS for this class?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ipums-data-sources-how-theyre-used-in-the-news&#34;&gt;IPUMS Data Sources &amp;amp; How they’re used in the News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#current-population-survey-cps&#34;&gt;Current Population Survey (CPS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#us-census-american-community-survey&#34;&gt;US Census &amp;amp; American Community Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#demographic-and-health-survey-dhs&#34;&gt;Demographic and Health Survey (DHS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#american-time-use-survey-atus&#34;&gt;American Time Use Survey (ATUS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ipums-health-surveys&#34;&gt;IPUMS Health Surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#national-health-interview-survey&#34;&gt;National Health Interview Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#medical-expenditure-panel-surveys&#34;&gt;Medical Expenditure Panel Surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#youth-risk-behavioral-surveillance-system&#34;&gt;Youth Risk Behavioral Surveillance System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IPUMS: Integrated Public Use Micro-data System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPUMS is a database / repository that we will be using for the group projects in class. You may only work with IPUMS data, which sounds like a constraint, but is actually a great opportunity to work with relatively clean, well-documented data that could include any number of possible topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipums.org/whatIsIPUMS.shtml&#34;&gt;What is IPUMS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPUMS provides census and survey data from around the world integrated across time and space. IPUMS integration and documentation makes it easy to study change, conduct comparative research, merge information across data types, and analyze individuals within family and community context. Data and services available free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPUMS has created the world’s largest accessible database of census microdata. IPUMS includes almost a billion records from U.S. censuses from 1790 to the present and over a billion records from the international censuses of over 100 countries. We have also harmonized survey data with over 30,000 integrated variables and 150 million records, including the Current Population Survey, the American Community Survey, the National Health Interview Survey, the Demographic and Health Surveys, and an expanding collection of labor force, health, and education surveys. In total, IPUMS currently disseminates integrated microdata describing 1.4 billion individuals drawn from over 750 censuses and surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;why-are-we-using-ipums-for-this-class&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Why are we using IPUMS for this class?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IPUMS user interface, data documentation, and having already “cleaned” much of the data will make your life substantially easier. Specifically, it will give you only the data you choose/need and remarkably better documented than many other sources of data you might find elsewhere. The benefit here is that you can focus instead on the actual task for this project - using your regression modeling skills you’re developing in the class - rather than wrangling unnecessary data. Given the breadth of the surveys / datasources included under the IPUMS umbrella, IPUMS should also serve a wide range of interests, especially economics, health, and social sciences. With 750 censuses/surveys, everyone in our class should be able to find a topic of interest from the IPUMS data. Last (but certainly not least), they have a R package called &lt;code&gt;ipumsr&lt;/code&gt; (package &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ipumsr&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and vignettes &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ipumsr/vignettes/ipums.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) to help import their data into R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ipums-data-sources-how-theyre-used-in-the-news&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;IPUMS Data Sources &amp;amp; How they’re used in the News&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the bigger surveys that IPUMS has worked to integrate over time get cited frequently in the press and used by other analysts, like Nathan Yau in his &lt;a href=&#34;blog&#34;&gt;Flowing Data&lt;/a&gt;. Although most of these examples aren’t of regression modeling per se, they should give a sense of some of the flavor for what data each survey has and the kinds of questions you can answer with each of the surveys. For more academic applications of these data, you could also see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipums.org/awardwinners.shtml&#34;&gt;IPUMS research award winners&lt;/a&gt; for some inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;current-population-survey-cps&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Current Population Survey (CPS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPUMS CPS harmonizes microdata from the monthly U.S. labor force survey, the Current Population Survey (CPS), covering the period 1962 to the present. Data include demographic information, rich employment data, program participation and supplemental data on topics such as fertility, tobacco use, volunteer activities, voter registration, computer and internet use, food security, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/tag/current-population-survey/&#34;&gt;FiveThirtyEight&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/33-million-americans-still-dont-have-health-insurance/&#34;&gt;33 Million Americans Still Don’t Have Health Insurance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/college-freshmen-are-more-politically-engaged-than-they-have-been-in-decades/&#34;&gt;College Freshmen Are More Politically Engaged Than They Have Been In Decades&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;NYTimes&lt;/em&gt;sts
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/11/28/upshot/what-the-tax-bill-would-look-like-for-25000-middle-class-families.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;What the Tax Bill Would Look Life for 25,000 Middle Class Families&lt;/a&gt; and a [companion, process piece on how that was built] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/insider/how-to-build-a-tax-calculator-thats-actually-useful.html&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/insider/how-to-build-a-tax-calculator-thats-actually-useful.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/09/18/upshot/black-white-wealth-gap-perceptions.html&#34;&gt;Whites have a huge wealth edge over blacks (but don’t know it)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flowing Data&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://flowingdata.com/2017/11/28/career-paths/&#34;&gt;Constructed Career Paths from Job Switching Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flowingdata.com/2017/05/02/shifting-incomes-for-young-people/&#34;&gt;Shifting Incomes for Young People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;us-census-american-community-survey&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;US Census &amp;amp; American Community Survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American Community Survey is administered by the Census Bureau and includes information annually in between the decennial Census on ~1% of the US population. American Community Survey has information on many different subjects of demographics, economics, and social well-being; some are listed here at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/acs/guidance/subjects.html&#34;&gt;Census.&lt;/a&gt; IPUMS has both the annual ACS and the decennial Census via &lt;a href=&#34;https://usa.ipums.org/usa/&#34;&gt;IPUMS USA&lt;/a&gt;. (Note: there are also international census data via &lt;a href=&#34;https://international.ipums.org/&#34;&gt;IPUMS International&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/tag/american-community-survey/&#34;&gt;FiveThirtyEight&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/same-sex-couples-are-more-domestic-in-more-tolerant-states/&#34;&gt;Same-Sex Couples Settle Down More Often in States That Welcome Them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forbes, Feb 8, 2018: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/petesaunders1/2018/02/08/comparing-americas-major-metro-housing-markets/#36b5429f29fc&#34;&gt;Comparing America’s Major Metro Housing Markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/09/15/the-average-american-spent-more-than-9-full-days-getting-to-and-from-work-last-year/&#34;&gt;The average American spent more than 9 full days getting to and from work last year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/10/25/is-100000-middle-class-in-america/?utm_term=.e2dda08f1475&#34;&gt;Is $100,000 middle class in America?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://flowingdata.com/tag/american-community-survey/&#34;&gt;Flowing Data&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flowingdata.com/2018/01/23/the-demographics-of-others/&#34;&gt;The Demographics of Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flowingdata.com/2016/03/03/marrying-age/&#34;&gt;Marrying Age: This is when Americans get married&lt;/a&gt;, or conversely…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flowingdata.com/2017/07/25/divorce-and-occupation/&#34;&gt;Divorce Rate by Occupation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mapmakerbot/&#34;&gt;Map Maker Bot&lt;/a&gt; automatically generates maps of the US using ACS data. Maybe some of the visuals will spark interest for a research topic!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;demographic-and-health-survey-dhs&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Demographic and Health Survey (DHS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPUMS-DHS facilitates analysis of Demographic and Health Surveys, administered in low- and middle-income countries since the 1980s. IPUMS-DHS contains thousands of consistently coded variables on the health and well-being of women, children, and births, for 22 African countries and India. There is detailed information on population, health status and health care, HIV and nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data are available via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.idhsdata.org/&#34;&gt;IPUMS DHS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Former Smith College GOV Prof. Kim Yi Dionne in Washington Post, Dec 1, 2017: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2017/12/01/its-world-aids-day-who-actually-needs-more-aids-awareness/?utm_term=.e7f416ec810b&#34;&gt;It’s World AIDS Day. Who actually needs more AIDS awareness?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quartz, Jan 29, 2018: &lt;a href=&#34;https://qz.com/1191272/economic-survey-2018-indias-preference-for-boys-has-produced-21-million-unwanted-girls/&#34;&gt;India’s preference for boys has produced 21 million “unwanted girls”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Economist. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.economist.com/news/middle-east-and-africa/21607897-amid-worries-about-kidnapped-girls-nigerias-traditions-are-unkind-too-bring-back&#34;&gt;Bring back the girls: Fertility and Son-preference in Nigeria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;american-time-use-survey-atus&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;American Time Use Survey (ATUS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ATUS is a nationally representative U.S. time diary survey for period since 2003. ATUS data facilitate analysis of the average amount of time per day individuals did various activities in a given day: how much someone worked, did household activities, engaged in leisure (e.g., TV watching) and sports activities, and providing childcare and eldercare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of these data are idiosyncratic and not ideal for our purposes. I would recommend not using these data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ipums-health-surveys&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IPUMS Health Surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;national-health-interview-survey&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;National Health Interview Survey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Health Interview Survey is a survey collecting information on the health, health care access, and health behaviors of the civilian, non-institutionalized U.S. population, with digital data files available from 1963 to present. IPUMS Health Surveys harmonizes these data and allows users to create custom NHIS data extracts for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NHIS data are used to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor progress towards national health objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate health policies and programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track changes in health behaviors and health care use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics included&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medical conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health insurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doctor’s office visits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Physical activity and other health behaviors&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaiser Family Foundation Data Notes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kff.org/disparities-policy/issue-brief/the-affordable-care-act-and-insurance-coverage-changes-by-sexual-orientation/&#34;&gt;The Affordable Care Act and Insurance Coverage Changes by Sexual Orientation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reuters. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-autism-trend/little-change-in-proportion-of-u-s-kids-with-autism-idUSKBN1FB2WO&#34;&gt;Little change in proportion of US kids with autism&lt;/a&gt;
-Washington Post &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp/2017/03/07/arthritis-afflicts-about-1-in-4-adults-in-the-u-s-cdc-report-finds/?utm_term=.d5b958f2131d&#34;&gt;Arthritis afflicts about 1 in 4 adults in the U.S., CDC report finds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;medical-expenditure-panel-surveys&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Medical Expenditure Panel Surveys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MEPS provides nationally representative, longitudinal data from 1996 to the present on health status, medical conditions, healthcare utilization, and healthcare expenditures for the U.S. civilian, non-institutionalized population. IPUMS MEPS harmonizes these data and allows users to create customized data extracts for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NPR, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/04/25/525475221/changes-to-federal-insurance-plans-could-hurt-families-of-chronically-ill-kids&#34;&gt;Changes To Federal Insurance Plans Could Hurt Families Of Chronically Ill Kids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaiser Health News &lt;a href=&#34;https://khn.org/news/despite-aca-cost-protections-most-adolescents-skip-regular-checkups/&#34;&gt;Despite ACA Cost Protections, Most Adolescents Skip Regular Checkups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;youth-risk-behavioral-surveillance-system&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Youth Risk Behavioral Surveillance System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPUMS YRBSS is a cross-sectional national survey of youth in grades 9-12 with emphasis on health risk behaviors that are often established during childhood and adolescence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tobacco use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;alcohol and other drug use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unintentional injuries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sexual behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unhealthy diet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inadequate physical activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.popdata.org/youthhealth/&#34;&gt;IPUMS YRBSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forming a Group</title>
      <link>/group/01-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/group/01-group/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;You’ll need to find a group of 3 (you and 2 others) to work together throughout the semester on a project with a topic of your choosing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have your group, please come up with a group name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, fill out &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSe3Wu2dsmn-8OYaWon88ApV9OHBXjyTxg2JTWUTNreAWO-ZFQ/viewform?usp=sf_link&#34;&gt;this Google Form&lt;/a&gt; with your group name and members.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Introduction</title>
      <link>/group/00-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/group/00-group/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#project-related-material&#34;&gt;Project related material&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#groups&#34;&gt;Groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#assignment&#34;&gt;Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#general-rules&#34;&gt;General Rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#timeline&#34;&gt;Timeline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#submission&#34;&gt;Submission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#proposals-draft-and-final&#34;&gt;Proposals (draft and final)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ipums-data&#34;&gt;IPUMS Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#health&#34;&gt;Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#economics&#34;&gt;Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#non-us-populations&#34;&gt;Non-US populations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#stem-higher-education&#34;&gt;STEM &amp;amp; Higher Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#time-use&#34;&gt;Time-Use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#content&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#final-products-report-and-presentation&#34;&gt;Final Products: Report and Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#report&#34;&gt;Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#content-1&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tone&#34;&gt;Tone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;project-related-material&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Project related material&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a major component of this class, you (and your group) will conduct a statistical study on a topic of your choice. This task will require you to write a project proposal, acquire and analyze relevant data, present your results orally to the class, and hand in a written report describing your study and its findings. Your project must involve fitting a regression model. The project is an opportunity to show off what you’ve learned about data analysis, visualization, and statistical inference. It is a major component of the class, and successful completion is required to pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;groups&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Groups&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will work in a group of three, of your choosing. For project related questions via email / Slack, please use your group name and cc/tag your group mates as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;assignment&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Assignment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should pose a problem that you find interesting and which may be addressed (at least in part) through the analysis of data. Many interesting quantitative questions (and perhaps even more uninteresting ones) involve the relationships among several variables. Recent projects have considered the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is gender pay gap in STEM workers?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is alcohol use associated with incidents of intimate partner violence?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How is social support related to physical health and obesity?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does prevalence of intergenerational households vary by region of the country?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How is income associated with total medical expenditures?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are there differences in skin cancer testing rates by education and race?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does the relationship between education and income vary by race/ethnicity?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should pose the problem that you want to solve as precisely as possible at the outset. You should also make a hypothesis, a priori(before you analyze the data), about the results you expect to see. You may not propose a question without a succinct main hypothesis of one explanatory variable and one response variable; you may have up to 2 secondary hypotheses that you also explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be using data from IPUMS (see link below to a description of IPUMS for this project)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might consider examples from previous Undergraduate Statistics Class Project winners to get a sense of the scope and presentation of a high quality project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;general-rules&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;General Rules&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may discuss your project with other students, but each group will have a different topic, so there is a limit to how much you can help each other. You may consult other sources for information about the non-statistical, substantive issues in your problem, but you should credit these sources in your report. Feel free to consult with us about statistical questions. To foreshadow the presentation: note that everyone is expected to speak during the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;timeline&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Timeline&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see the syllabus for due dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submission&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submission&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All deliverables described above must be delivered electronically via Moodle by 11:55pm (five minutes before midnight) on the dates above. Only one person from the group should submit the group’s product for each checkpoint (with the exception of the Group Dynamic, which is individual).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;proposals-draft-and-final&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Proposals (draft and final)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count on brainstorming at least half a dozen serious ideas before you can groom one of them into a mature proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, the choice of topic is left up to you. Try to pick something that’s interesting yet substantial and worth studying, and aim for a topic that you think nobody has tried before; remember that part of your overall grade will be based on originality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ipums-data&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;IPUMS Data&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the right data to answer your particular question is part of your responsibility for this assignment. You may also want to refine your research question so that it can be more clearly addressed by the data that you found. But be creative!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to help you narrow your choice and focus on appropriate data sets, as well as to maximize my ability to help you, projects can (and must) use data any of the IPUMS data, which are listed below and highlighted in more detail in the HTML file attached at the bottom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPUMS has many census, national and international survey datasets that are well-documented and cleaned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;health&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National Health Interview Survey (health status, trends)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medical Expenditure Panel Survey (health care, health care spending)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;economics&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Economics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current Population Survey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Census &amp;amp; American Community Survey Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;non-us-populations&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Non-US populations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demographic and Health Surveys (low- and middle-income countries)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International Census Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;stem-higher-education&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;STEM &amp;amp; Higher Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;time-use&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time-Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most projects will measure a quantitative or a binary response variable (we will cover logistic regression for binary outcomes after Spring Break and in enough time that you can complete the project).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I respond to your initial proposal, you will revise it (perhaps starting with a different dataset), then submit a new proposal that addresses our feedback. Supply essentially the same information required for the initial proposal, but give a bit more detail on the rationale for the study (i.e., why does this question matter? what is its relevance outside of this class?), revised hypotheses, and clearer proposed methods to test those hypotheses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;content&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Content&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your initial and revised proposals should contain the following content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Group Members:&lt;/em&gt; List the members of your group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Title:&lt;/em&gt; Your title&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose: &lt;/em&gt;Describe the general topic/phenomenon you want to study, as well some focused questions that you hope to answer and specific hypotheses that you intend to assess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data: &lt;/em&gt;Describe the data that you plan to use, with specifications of where it can be found (URL) and a short description. Which IPUMS surveys, in which years? Describe the source of the data - was it a survey, and if so, how were people selected and how was the data collected - in a few sentences. You can look to the IPUMS descriptions for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Population: &lt;/em&gt;Specify what the observational units are (i.e. the rows of the data frame), describe the larger population/phenomenon to which you’ll try to generalize, and (if appropriate) estimate roughly how many such individuals there are in the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Response Variable: &lt;/em&gt;What the response variable? What are its units? Estimate the range of possible values that it may take on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explanatory Variables: &lt;/em&gt;You should have one, primary explanatory variable that is your main hypothesis. You may have other explanatory variables associated with secondary hypotheses (again, no more than 2). Then you will also have explanatory variables that you want to control for – factors that may be associated with your primary explanatory and your response variables that you want to include in your multiple regression model to adjust your main association for those competing explanations. Demographics (age, sex, race) and socioeconomic status are common ones for individual-level survey data. Carefully define each variable and describe how each was measured (self-report/direct observation). For categorical variables, list the possible categories; for quantitative variables, specify the units of measurement. You may want to add more variables later on, but you should have at least the explanatory variables associated with your hypotheses and 5 additional variables you plan to control for already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;final-products-report-and-presentation&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Final Products: Report and Presentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;report&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Report&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report itself should be a 3-page paper reporting the results of your project that includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Background/significance of the research, and a clearly stated research question an hypothesis/hypotheses. (What you’re doing and why)
In a few paragraphs (1-3), you should explain clearly and precisely what your research question is, why it is interesting, and what contribution you have made towards answering that question. You should give an overview of the specifics of your model, but not the full details. Most readers never make it past the introduction, so this is your chance to hook the reader, and is in many ways the most important part of the paper! You should have at least 1-3 citations to previous research in this area to support your ideas and show what has already been done and what gap you are filling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods:&lt;/em&gt; The methods used to obtain and analyze the data (How you’re doing it)
This should include a brief description of your data set. Some questions you should consider (though this is not an exhaustive list): What is the population that was sampled? How was the sample collected? What variables are included in your analysis? Where did they come from? What are units of measurement? How much missing data did you have and what did you do about it? How did you choose which variables to include in your model? What kind of model did you fit? How did you evaluate the assumptions of this model? Don’t tell us the results, just tell us the steps you took. Think of this is as like in a lab report that is reproducible – someone else should be able to download the same data, follow your steps, and get the same results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; The results of the analysis - both descriptive text and tables, charts, or graphs (What you found)
This section is an explanation of what your model tells us about the research question. You should interpret coefficients in context and explain their relevance. What does your model tell us about your research question and hypothesis? You may want to include negative results, but be careful about how you interpret them. For example, you may want to say something along the lines of: “we found no evidence that explanatory variable xxis associated with response variable yy,” or “explanatory variable xx did not provide any additional explanatory power above what was already conveyed by explanatory variable zz.” On other hand, you probably shouldn’t claim: “there is no relationship between xx and yy,” which is akin to accepting the null.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discussion:&lt;/em&gt; A discussion of the research, the limitations of the current research, reasonableness of any assumptions made, possibilities of future work/studies that should be conducted, etc. (How your findings help answer your question, why your findings matter (or don’t!))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A summary of your findings and a discussion of their limitations. First, remind the reader of the question that you originally set out to answer, and summarize your findings. Second, discuss the limitations of your model, and what could be done to improve it. You might also want to do the same for your data. Also include a few sentences about the strength(s) of your analysis / study. This is your last opportunity to clarify the scope of your findings before a journalist misinterprets them and makes wild extrapolations! Protect yourself by being clear about what is not implied by your research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire written summary must be no more than 3 pages (single spaced, Arial 11pt font with standard 1 inch margins).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the 3 pages with the main content you should have a title page which includes:
- The title of the project and
- a one-paragraph abstract (summary) of the entire project (&amp;lt;150 words)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The abstract should not consist of more than 5 or 6 sentences, but should relate what you studied and what you found. It need only convey a general sense of what you actually did. The purpose of the abstract is to give a prospective reader enough information to decide if they want to read the full paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References should be listed at the end of the report and do not count against the 3 page limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: You might submit a 4.5 page Word document that is consists of the title page, 3 pages of text/graphs and half page of references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Optional) You may include up to 5 additional pages of information about your project in an appendix (as part of the single uploaded file),this could include secondary analysis results that didn’t fit, figures to check your model assumptions, descriptive statistics / figures, extra charts/tables, etc. The optional appendix may be reviewed, but you should not plan on it. Your material in the 3 page report should be self-contained; no information deemed critical to the evaluation of your project should be included in the Appendix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your report should be submitted via email as an R Markdown (.Rmd) file and the corresponding rendered output (.pdf) file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;content-1&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Content&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should not need to present all of the R code that you wrote throughout the process of working on this project. Rather, the technical report should contain the minimal set of R code that is necessary to understand your results and findings in full. If you make a claim, it must be justified by explicit calculation. A knowledgeable reviewer should be able to compile your .Rmd file without modification, and verify every statement that you have made. All of the R code necessary to produce your figures and tables must appear in the technical report. In short, the technical report should enable a reviewer to reproduce your work in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical report is not simply a dump of all the R code you wrote during this project. Rather, it is a narrative, with technical details, that describes how you addressed your research question. You should not present tables or figures without a written explanation of the information that is supposed to be conveyed by that table or figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind the distinction between data and information. Data is just numbers, whereas information is the result of analyzing that data and digesting it into meaningful ideas that human beings can understand. Your technical report should allow a reviewer to follow your steps from converting data into information. For example, simply displaying a table with the means and standard deviations of your variables is not meaningful. Writing a sentence that reiterates the content of the table (e.g. “the mean of variable xx was 34.5 and the standard deviation was 2.8…”) is equally meaningless. What you should strive to do is interpret these values in context (e.g. “although variables x1 and x2 have similar means, the spread of x1 is much larger, suggesting…”). Think of the text in the result section as a way to walk the reader through your tables / figures and to convey results that are important but not included in a table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should present figures and tables in your technical report in context. These items should be understandable on their own – in the sense that they have understandable titles, axis labels, legends, and captions. Someone glancing through your technical report should be able to make sense of your figures and tables without having to read the entire report. That said, you should also include a discussion of what you want the reader to learn from your figures and tables. Use the &lt;code&gt;stargazer&lt;/code&gt; package and consider plotting your results in a figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tone&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Tone&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document should be written for peer reviewers, who comprehend statistics at least as well as you do. You should aim for a level of complexity that is more statistically sophisticated than an article in the Science section of The New York Times, but less sophisticated than an academic journal. [Chance magazine might provide a good example.] For example, you may use terms that that you will likely never see in the Times(e.g. bootstrap), but should not dwell on technical points with no obvious ramifications for the reader (e.g. reporting F-statistics). Your goal for this paper is to convince a statistically-minded reader (e.g. a student in this class, or a student from another school who has taken an introductory statistics class) that you have addressed an interesting research question in a meaningful way. Even a reader with no background in statistics should be able to read your paper and get the gist of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Proposal</title>
      <link>/group/02-group-finalproposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/group/02-group-finalproposal/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#content-of-the-proposal&#34;&gt;Content of the Proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#group-members-name&#34;&gt;Group Members / Name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#purpose&#34;&gt;Purpose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#population&#34;&gt;Population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#response-variable&#34;&gt;Response Variable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#explanatory-variables&#34;&gt;Explanatory Variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#going-from-draft-into-final-proposal&#34;&gt;Going from Draft into Final Proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submit this as a pdf to moodle. The pdf doesn’t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to be made R - you can make it in Google Docs or Word, just saved as a pdf - especially for the draft, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://sds291.netlify.com/group/02-modelfinalgroupproposal.rmd&#34;&gt;here is an &lt;code&gt;.RMD&lt;/code&gt; file for the Model Group Draft Proposal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;content-of-the-proposal&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Content of the Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;group-members-name&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Group Members / Name&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List the members of your group and your group name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;title&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposed title of your project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;purpose&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the general topic/phenomenon you want to study, as well some focused questions that you hope to answer and specific hypotheses that you intend to assess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;data&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the data that you plan to use, with specifications of where it can be found (URL) and a short description. Which IPUMS surveys, in which years? Describe the source of the data - was it a survey, and if so, how were people selected and how was the data collected - in a few sentences. You can look to the IPUMS descriptions for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;population&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Population&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specify what the observational units are (i.e. the rows of the data frame), describe the larger population/phenomenon to which you’ll try to generalize, and (if appropriate) estimate roughly how many such individuals there are in the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;response-variable&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Response Variable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the response variable? What are its units? Estimate the range of possible values that it may take on. [&lt;em&gt;Most projects will use a quantitative or a binary response variable (we will cover logistic regression for binary outcomes after Spring Break and in enough time that you can complete the project)&lt;/em&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;explanatory-variables&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Explanatory Variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should have one, primary explanatory variable that is your main hypothesis. You may have other explanatory variables associated with secondary hypotheses (no more than 2 secondary hypotheses, or three hypotheses total).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you will also have explanatory variables that you want to control for – variables that may be associated with your primary explanatory and your response variables that you want to include in your multiple regression model to adjust your main association for those competing explanations. Demographics (age, sex, race) and socioeconomic status are common ones for individual-level survey data. Your final regression model must include at least 5 confounding variables beyond your main explanatory variable that is included in your hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carefully define each variable and describe how each was measured (self-report/direct observation). For categorical variables, list the possible categories; for quantitative variables, specify the units of measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;going-from-draft-into-final-proposal&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Going from Draft into Final Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I respond to your initial proposal (within a week or so of submitting), you will revise it (perhaps starting with a different dataset), then submit a new proposal that addresses our feedback. Note that you may well need to start from scratch, so be thoughtful but open during the drafting process, and know that there will need to be revision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also want to summarize what’s different from your Draft to your Final proposal to illustrate the work you did in the revision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Final Proposal should include essentially the same information required as the initial proposal, but with more detail on the rationale for the study (i.e., why does this question matter? what is its relevance outside of this class?), revised hypotheses, and clearer proposed methods to test those hypotheses. See the Model Group Draft Proposal for an example of a fully fleshed out, comprehensive example of a final proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Group Final Proposal</title>
      <link>/group/02-modelfinalgroupproposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/group/02-modelfinalgroupproposal/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#template-for-this-file&#34;&gt;Template for This File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#group-name-and-members&#34;&gt;Group Name and Members&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#purpose-and-hypotheses&#34;&gt;Purpose and Hypotheses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#population&#34;&gt;Population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#response-variable&#34;&gt;Response Variable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#explanatory-variables&#34;&gt;Explanatory Variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#primary-hypothesis&#34;&gt;Primary hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#secondary-hypotheses&#34;&gt;Secondary hypotheses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;template-for-this-file&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Template for This File&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sds291.netlify.com/group/02-modelfinalgroupproposal.rmd&#34;&gt;Here is the raw &lt;code&gt;.RMD&lt;/code&gt; file that generated this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;group-name-and-members&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Group Name and Members&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!---List your group&#39;s name and the first and last name of all group members here---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Model” Group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prof. Capistrant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tyra Banks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenny Shimizu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;title&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!---Come up with a working title for your project based on your topic and focus.---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality of Life among Sexual Minority Cancer Survivors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;purpose-and-hypotheses&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Purpose and Hypotheses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!---Describe the general topic/phenomenon you want to study, as well some focused questions that you hope to answer and specific hypotheses that you intend to assess.* 

*You should have 1 primary hypothesis of a single assocation between a response-explanatory variable and 1-2 secondary hypotheses, like a secondary outcome and/or testing whether your main asssociation varies (i.e., interacts with) by some third variable---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on the self-reported quality of life and general health of sexual minorities (i.e, gay/bisexual/lesbian identified persons) with a history of cancer. There is some evidence that sexual minorities with history of cancer may have worse quality of life than heterosexual counterparts. This difference may be pronounced for those with sex-specific cancers, where the interactions with providers or the changes to one’s sexual/gender identity matter differently for sexual minorities. There may also be differences within sexual minorities by race, as per intersectionality theory. This project will test that association in a large, nationally-representative sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;primary hypothesis&lt;/strong&gt; is that, among those with history of cancer, sexual minorities will have lower quality of life than heterosexual counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;secondary hypotheses&lt;/strong&gt; are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The difference in quality of life between sexual minorities and heterosexual cancer survivors will be larger for sex-specific cancers (e.g., breast or prostate) than other cancers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sexual minorities of color will have worse outcomes than white sexual minorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;data&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!---Describe the data that you plan to use, with specifications of where it can be found (URL) and a short description. We will discuss data management techniques in the coming weeks, but for now you should simply list multiple sources if you have them.---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study will use data from IPUMS-NHIS. National Health Interview Survey (NHIS) annually surveys the US non-institutionalized population about their health, health care, and health conditions. NHIS first asked questions about sexual orientation in 2013. Because sexual minority populations with cancer will be relatively rare, we will pool data from 2013-2016 to maximize the sample size and increase statistical power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;population&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Population&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!---Specify what the observational units are (i.e. the rows of the data frame), describe the larger population/phenomenon to which you&#39;ll try to generalize, and (if appropriate) estimate roughly how many such individuals there are in the population.---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NHIS includes individual survey respondents such that each observation is a different person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NHIS is an annual, cross-sectional household survey. Individuals are clustered in households, particularly that one adult and one random child are included from each household. Since we are only interested in adults, each observation should be independent of the others as none of them will be co-residents in the same household. Moreover, although we are pooling data from multiple years, since the survey is cross-sectional, the independence assumption is not violated with repeated measures on the same person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this topicis specific to those with a history of cancer, we will filter the data to include only those with history of cancer using the variable &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/CANCEREV#codes_section&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CANCEREV&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Thus, the population of inference will be the US adult population with cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;response-variable&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Response Variable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!---What is the response variable? What are its units? Estimate the range of possible values that it may take on.---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response variable will be a measure of self-rated health: “Would you say your health in general is excellent, very good, good, fair, or poor?”. The variable is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/HEALTH#codes_section&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HEALTH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in IPUMS-NHIS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response options are: 1=Excellent; 2=Very good; 3=Good; 4=Fair; 5=Poor; 7=Refused; 9=Don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will create a new, two-level variable from these responses that indicates good health: Excellent/Very good vs. Good/Fair/Poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use logistic regression to model this outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;explanatory-variables&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Explanatory Variables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!---You should have one, primary explanatory variable that is your main hypothesis. You may have other explanatory variables associated with secondary hypotheses (again, no more than 2).*

*Then you will also have explanatory variables that you want to control for -- factors that may be associated with your primary explanatory and your response variables that you want to include in your multiple regression model to adjust your main association for those competing explanations. Demographics (age, sex, race) and socioeconomic status are common ones for individual-level survey data.*

*Carefully define each variable and describe how each was measured (self-report/direct observation). For categorical variables, list the possible categories; for quantitative variables, specify the units of measurement. You may want to add more variables later on, but you should have at least the explanatory variables associated with your hypotheses and 5 additional variables you plan to control for already.---&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;primary-hypothesis&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Primary hypothesis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated above in “Population”, we will restrict this analysis to those who have cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary hypotheses will use a variable indicating sexual orientation . We will create this variable from two different sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals self-report their sexual orientation (&lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/SEXORIEN#codes_section&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;SEXORIEN&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in NHIS) in response to a question: “Which of the following best represents how you think of yourself?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer options: 1=Gay; 2=Straight, that is, not gay; 3=Bisexual; 4=Something else; 5=I don’t know the answer; 7=Refused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will combine responses and create a variable that indicates being either gay/bisexual vs. straight/something else/don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test of our hypothesis will be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(H_0: \beta1=0\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(H_A: \beta1\neq0\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from the regression model:
&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[logit(GoodHealth) = \beta_0 + \beta_1 SexualMinority  +\beta&amp;#39;X\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(\beta&amp;#39;X\)&lt;/span&gt; is a vector of covariates included to control for potential confounding. They are described below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;secondary-hypotheses&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Secondary hypotheses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. The difference in quality of life between sexual minorities and heterosexual cancer survivors will be larger for sex-specific cancers (e.g., breast or prostate) than other cancers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will create an indicator variable of those with breast, ovarian, cervical, uterine, testicular or prostate cancer vs. other kinds of cancer. NHIS asks questions about cancer type at every year between 2013-2016, detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/group?id=conditions_cancer&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will test this hypothesis with an interaction between sexual orientation and sex-specific cancer type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test of our hypothesis will be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(H_0: \beta3=0\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(H_A: \beta3\neq0\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
\begin{split}
logit(GoodHealth) = \beta_0 + \beta_1 SexualMinority + \beta_2 SexSpecificCancers + \\
 \beta_3 (SexualMinority \times SexSpecificCancers) +\beta&amp;#39;X
\end{split}
\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- If you&#39;re going to use a dichotomous outcome, don&#39;t worry about specifying the regression equation since we haven&#39;t covered it yet, but think about what it would be. If you&#39;re planning to use a linear model, you should be able to write out the regression equation for the test of each hypothesis --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. Sexual minorities of color will have worse outcomes than white sexual minorities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This information comes from a question about the respondent’s race: “What race or races do you consider yourself to be? Please select 1 or more of these categories.” IPUMS included 5 categories: White, Black/African American, American Indian/Alaskan Native, Asian, Multiple Race in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/RACENEW#codes_section&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;RACENEW&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will try to test each racial group separately, but we may have to collapse into an indicator/binary variable of white vs. non-white race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(H_0: \beta3=0\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(H_A: \beta3\neq0\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
\begin{split}
logit(GoodHealth) = \beta_0 + \beta_1 SexualMinority + \beta_2 NonWhiteRace + \\
\beta_3 (SexualMinority \times NonWhiteRace) +\beta&amp;#39;X
\end{split}
\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis will be restricted to only sexual minorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;potential-confounders&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Potential Confounders&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We suspect that demographic and socio-economic factors will be important to control for, as they would be associated with both sexual orientation and with health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Age &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/group?id=demographic_core&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;AGE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sex &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/group?id=demographic_core&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;SEX&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marital Status &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/group?id=demographic_core&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;MARSTCOHAB&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Race &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/group?id=demographic_ethnicity&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;RACENEW&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hispanic Ethnicity &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/group?id=demographic_ethnicity&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HISPYN&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education &lt;a href=&#34;https://nhis.ipums.org/nhis-action/variables/group?id=economic_education&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;EDUC&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might want to control for other health characteristics like smoking, physical activity, diet, and mental health. We will explore that in our analysis after we review the literature to find what is most commonly done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
