<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs | Multiple Regression</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
      <atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blogs</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/social-image.png</url>
      <title>Blogs</title>
      <link>/blog/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Logistics</title>
      <link>/blog/02-2ndsurvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/02-2ndsurvey/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#times-for-class-via-zoom&#34;&gt;Times for “Class” via Zoom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#student-hours&#34;&gt;Student Hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#group-project&#34;&gt;Group Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#covid-19-specific-examples-in-class&#34;&gt;COVID-19 Specific Examples in Class&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#other-thoughts&#34;&gt;Other thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to those who completed the second survey about preferences for class logistics / timings. I wanted to report back to you on what you said, how I interpreted that, and what I’m proposing as a result. There’s a &lt;strong&gt;summary&lt;/strong&gt; at the top in case you just the highlights, and then some more details and actual data/responses below for more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;summary&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll have “class” Monday/Wednesdays from 1:20-2:35PM (Eastern) via Zoom*. These will be recorded and posted to Moodle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll have student hours via Zoom* on Tuesdays/Thursdays from 8-9AM and 4-5PM Eastern. These will also be recorded and posted to Moodle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll use Slack for all other course communications outside of those Zoom sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group project is definitely optional. Groups who are interested in continuing their work – or people who want an individual alternative to a group project – please be in touch with me directly via Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use some COVID-19 examples in class (primarily in the first week), but cautiously and with an opt-out, alternative activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href=&#34;https://sds291.netlify.com/syllabus/&#34;&gt;syllabus addendum&lt;/a&gt; that I encourage you to read for other course specifics moving forward if you haven’t already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*I’m still sorting out how best to share the Zoom links – I think Google Calendar is easiest – and will post them to Slack in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;details&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;times-for-class-via-zoom&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Times for “Class” via Zoom&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sds291.netlify.com/break/class_times.png&#34; alt=&#34;test&#34; width=&#34;550&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m taking from this that most people can do Section 1 - 1:20 to 2:35 - and am proposing that we use that time slot for our Zoom meeting for “Class”. Since not everyone can make that time, I don’t think having people from both sections will be troublesome. And it frees up more time for student hours as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially suggested times that would move from our current course block to accomodate our different time zones, and (the next morning) got an email from the Provost who strongly encouraged us to keep any real-time learning during the same course block to minimize conflicts. So, I changed the question about availability during the course times and by doing so lost the data from those who responded to the earlier version of the question. I botched this one – my apologies for that, and for any confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;student-hours&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Student Hours&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student hours are going to be more useful than ever, especially for those who will be watching videos of material and want to get questions answered. This is especially true for students who are home in South/East Asia and where class time is going to be in the middle of the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/blog/02-2ndSurvey_files/figure-html/student%20hours%20-%20plot-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There aren’t a lot of surprises here, but it’s still helpful to see and walk through so you know what your classmates prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eastern time folks have a pretty symmetric distribution, with preferences more for mid-day/afternoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Eastern US (primarily Pacific time) preferes afternoons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Those outside the US are best served by early mornings or later evenings in Eastern Time US since you’re 9-13 hours ahead, so 8AM is somewhere between 5-9PM for you, and 9PM is between 6-10AM).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no perfect overlap here, and I’m not in a position to be having multiple 12 hour days for something morning, afternoon, and night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m proposing 1 hour of student hours via Zoom on Tuesdays and Thursdays at 8 AM Eastern, 4PM Eastern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;group-project&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Group Project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sds291.netlify.com/break/project_feelings.png&#34; alt=&#34;test&#34; height=&#34;550&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of you agreed with making the project optional, and about half seemed to think they would keep working on it. I’m &lt;em&gt;more than happy&lt;/em&gt; to support those who do want to keep going. I’ll let you talk amongst yourselves and just get in touch with me about where you stand on that, and we can just work directly and/or make “optional” assignments if enough groups are still going to be working on it that some shared structure and timeline would be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;covid-19-specific-examples-in-class&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;COVID-19 Specific Examples in Class&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sds291.netlify.com/break/covid_specific.png&#34; alt=&#34;test&#34; height=&#34;550&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of you were interested in using COVID-19 related examples in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also &lt;em&gt;totally&lt;/em&gt; hear those who don’t and want to honor that. I won’t make any required work COVID-19 related, just for practice in-class, and will offer alternative exercises for practice with different topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll also come up with some material for a kind of public health 101 sort of presentation, and will probably have that during the second week that we’re back (so the week of April 6th). Stay tuned on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;other-thoughts&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the other ideas, repsonses, and feeling that you shared. Especially those who shared that they were having a hard time – I appreciate knowing how you’re doing, and want to support you for success in the class. Some of these ideas will be easier to talk through “together” rather than reporting back and oversimplifying the points. But, I just wanted to be sure you know I read and appreciated what else you included even if it’s not mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Forward After Spring Break</title>
      <link>/blog/01-rlsurvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/01-rlsurvey/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-kinds-of-activities-should-we-be-doing&#34;&gt;What kinds of activities should we be doing?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#where-are-you-all-now&#34;&gt;Where are you all now?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#and-what-does-that-mean-for-when-we-should-have-class-via-zoom&#34;&gt;And what does that mean for when we should have class via Zoom?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#time-for-the-course&#34;&gt;Time for the course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of you will remember the survey we did in class the Wednesday before spring break. This was really helpful for me to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understand the environment you’ll be learning in for the rest of the semester and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guide some important decisions for how to structure the class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are some of the results of what you said in that poll and some reflections from me about what that suggests as to how we move forward. Not everything you answered is included, especially things where there was pretty uniform/universal answer (i.e., nearly everyone had a laptop). Instead, I wanted to illustrate to you how I used your information to inform the plan for how to move forward – and for you to know what your classmates are facing in their learning – for the rest of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-kinds-of-activities-should-we-be-doing&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What kinds of activities should we be doing?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/blog/01-RLSurvey_files/figure-html/activityplot-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my read of this graph, people would prefer that we:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do more or less the same syllabus and schedule, that is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivered via Zoom (and recorded for (re-)watching), with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote office hours (either Zoom and/or Slack).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;where-are-you-all-now&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Where are you all now?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;and-what-does-that-mean-for-when-we-should-have-class-via-zoom&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And what does that mean for when we should have class via Zoom?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/blog/01-RLSurvey_files/figure-html/timezone-plot-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of you are in the U.S., primarily in the East coast/time zone. If we are indeed keeping class in real time, an afternoon class probably still works to accomodate those in the western time zones. For those out of the U.S., the best compromise will be to record lectures and have them posted to Moodle for you to watch. I’ll plan office hours that are more in line with the time differences - either early AM Eastern (~7AM) / afternoon or evening in Asia or later evening (10PM) / morning Asia, at least one of either per week. I’ll make a specific poll to see which of those options you’d prefer – stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;time-for-the-course&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Time for the course&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/blog/01-RLSurvey_files/figure-html/time%20for%20class-plot-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of you expect to have about the same amount of time as you did when you were on campus to dedicate to this class. I fully expect that your responses on Wednesday before spring break may have been optimistic and have changed now a few weeks into this reality. Moreover, about 30% of you thought you would have less time. I think the best approach here is minimal and realistic expectations so that everyone feels set up for success. Practically this means, I’m planning to make less required work and offering more recommended additional problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who can do more, you’re welcome to - and the sky is the limit there. There are some (12%) who said you might have &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; time. If you find yourself wanting substantially more work - or a bigger scope of work - there are many possibilities for additional regression modeling work within my own research projects and/or plenty of other data. I will come up with a few ideas of how to structure this and will look for more input from you all soon. If you have thoughts in the meantime, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
