<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignment details | Multiple Regression</title>
    <link>/assignment/</link>
      <atom:link href="/assignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Assignment details</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <image>
      <url>/img/social-image.png</url>
      <title>Assignment details</title>
      <link>/assignment/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Home Exam 1</title>
      <link>/assignment/01-take-home-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/01-take-home-exam/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#overall-instructions&#34;&gt;Overall Instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#guidelines-for-the-exam&#34;&gt;Guidelines for the Exam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-you-cannot-do&#34;&gt;What you cannot do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-you-can-do&#34;&gt;What you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#some-general-suggestions&#34;&gt;Some general suggestions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note of explanation&lt;/em&gt;: I’m (now) calling this an exam, and doing so reluctantly. Having two different kinds of projects seemed to confuse some, which I can understand but was not my intent. I didn’t want to call this an exam because just the word test or exam heightens peoples’ anxiety, mostly unnecessarily (or disproportionately). Numerically this is equivalent to ~2 homework/problem sets, so I would encourage you to think about this as just like a bigger problem set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;overall-instructions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Overall Instructions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The assignment is &lt;a href=&#34;http://sds291.netlify.com/exam/take-home-exam.html&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; [&lt;em&gt;note, this was last updated with clarifications on Wednesday at ~5:00pm&lt;/em&gt; ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are three sections: A, B and C. A &amp;amp; B (mostly) cover the same thing and should be numbered accordingly (A1, B1, etc.). C is not graded, it just asks for your reflection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is not an &lt;code&gt;.rmd&lt;/code&gt; template. You can use one from a problem set or start a blank file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The file should be knitted to a &lt;code&gt;.pdf.&lt;/code&gt; and submitted with your &lt;code&gt;.rmd&lt;/code&gt; file on Moodle, just like a homework/problem set. Check your section’s moodle page for more details on where exactly to submit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be safe, should include your code in the knitted output, which you can do with the following command in your first code chunk (it’s already there in the HW templates:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;knitr::opts_chunk$set(echo = TRUE)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be clear and organized about your output, and make it clear where you are getting your numbers/answers from. For example, if you have a summary output of a model under question X, and you answering question M with something that comes from the output you have in question X, just refer back to Question X in your answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re formatting equations with Markdown, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://sds291.netlify.com/resources/equations/&#34;&gt;the resources section of the course site&lt;/a&gt; for some suggestions on key symbols and formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can read in the data directly, as below:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;data&amp;lt;-read.csv(&amp;quot;http://sds291.netlify.com/exam/291birthweight.csv&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;guidelines-for-the-exam&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Guidelines for the Exam&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-you-cannot-do&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What you cannot do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exam is to be done completely independently: you may not talk to or work with anyone about the exam before the exam period closes (2/17/20 at 12:00pm Noon). All code and answers must be entirely your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re expected to abide by the college honor code about this exam. Any allegations or suspicion of violations of these policies or the honor code are taken extremely seriously and will be reported to the honor board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t cheat. Please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-you-can-do&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can ask me questions to clarify any logistical piece, phrasing of the questions, or other similar details about the exam. Please DM me on slack with questions and I will likely answer them for everyone so that everyone has the same information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also be having student hours on Wednesday (11-1pm). Note that these are a different time than usual student hours on Wednesday. I can address both clarifying questions for the exam and review concepts that we’ve covered so far in class, but I cannot speak to the exam content directly. For example, if you’re wondering about how to interpret the slope, bring examples from the book, from class, or previous problem sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can ask Stat TAs about general concepts for the exam in a similar way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use your book. In fact, I’d strongly encourage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use your class notes – labs, slides, notes you’ve taken, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can google for help if needed. You shouldn’t need any &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; code you haven’t already seen in class, and much of the advice on the internet is spotty in quality, so I would take it with a grain of salt. But you can use the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;some-general-suggestions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Some general suggestions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of these concepts are subjective and may not have totally clear right or wrong answers. The safe bet is always to explain your rationale sufficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the questions are pretty explicit about what you should be interpreting, but when in doubt, ask.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep things organized, make it clear what your answer is (especially in a longer answer that can wander and make it hard to get your take away message), include everything (output, figures, etc.) you need for that particular answer (or refer clearly to where it is if you don’t want to reproduct it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homework 2 will not be returned before this exam is due. There will not be an answer set distributed. If you have questions about homework 2, please come to office hours or clarify concepts with the Stat TAs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Problem set 1</title>
      <link>/assignment/01-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/01-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#required&#34;&gt;Required&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#recommended&#34;&gt;Recommended&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#template-.rmd-file&#34;&gt;Template &lt;code&gt;.RMd&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#submit-on-moodle&#34;&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;required&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Required&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions 1.19, 1.21 (2nd Edition) or 1.8, 1.9 (1st Edition)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;recommended&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Recommended&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question 1.23 (2nd Edition) or 1.10 (1st Edition)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Note: these questions will expect that you will have fit the regression model before characterizing the residuals]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;template-.rmd-file&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Template &lt;code&gt;.RMd&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a template RMarkdown file for thiese questions &lt;a href=&#34;http://sds291.netlify.com/HW/SDS291_HW1_Template.Rmd&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; The link will download the &lt;code&gt;.RMd&lt;/code&gt; template file, which you can upload to the server as we did in class or open in the desktop version of RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submit-on-moodle&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the Homework 1 submission on Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;. If your registration is still in process and you don’t yet have Moodle access, you can submit it via email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0. Getting Started</title>
      <link>/assignment/00-assign-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/00-assign-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#initial-course-administration-tasks&#34;&gt;Initial Course Administration Tasks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#getting-started-with-r-refreshing-statistics&#34;&gt;Getting started with &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; Refreshing Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;initial-course-administration-tasks&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial Course Administration Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few small, administrative things to get started. These should have done during the first week of class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the syllabus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/STAT2-Modeling-Regression-Ann-Cannon-ebook-dp-B07K6Y99J3/dp/B07K6Y99J3/ref=mt_kindle?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;me=&amp;amp;qid=1579815019&#34;&gt;the textbook&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;amp; see notes about buying the book in the syllabus)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.polleverywhere.com/mobile&#34;&gt;PollEverywhere app&lt;/a&gt; to your phone or a device that you’ll have with you in the classroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up an account with &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.cloud/&#34;&gt;RStudio Cloud&lt;/a&gt; (easiest via Google with your Smith account). We will not be using the RStudio Cloud exclusively, but we will need to use it at a least a few points during the semester.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://join.slack.com/t/sds291-spring2020/shared_invite/enQtOTI0MzIwMjMwOTE3LTk1MjFmZTA4YjNjZmYxYTU4MTNiYjU3MWFhYTQ4MzNjNDkxYjZjMTE2YjE0N2Q4MmFmZmI2NTE3NTI2MzY2Mjc&#34;&gt;course Slack&lt;/a&gt; and post an animal gif in the channel for your section (Section 01: 1:20-2:35, or Section 02: 2:45 - 4:00pm). If you’re new to Slack, look through the Resources section of this page for some more information to get started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a 1-2 songs to &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/70l14LCdw5XOAyk1RHeuAO?si=Enp-jrtiSeKWhU4XYueiqg&#34;&gt;a playlist for our class&lt;/a&gt;. I like playing music at the beginning of class and during in-class work time (there will be a lot), so add something you’d like to hear. See more &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.spotify.com/us/article/create-playlists-with-your-friends/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; about adding to a collaborative playlist. If you don’t have a Spotify account or have trouble adding songs directly to Spotify, just add the song title and artist in &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1L_hHXNMI09c-XU1cTnEb5iivll3PYzBmfmdurVnYEww/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;this google sheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;getting-started-with-r-refreshing-statistics&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Getting started with &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; Refreshing Statistics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New to &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;? Feeling rusty on your introductory statistics material?*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t fret – we’ll do this all together, no need to feel like you have to do any prep before class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to practice &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;, especially during the first few weeks of semester when the workload is a little lighter, try the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.cloud/learn/primers&#34;&gt;primers in RStudio Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, especially the first four (don’t worry about iterate or write functions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look back at your intro stats text book, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B-DHaDEbiOGkRHNndUlBaHVmaGM/edit&#34;&gt;this open source textbook&lt;/a&gt;. You might want to review normal distributions, tests of differences in means (t-tests), ANOVA, and interpretation of p-values and confidence intervals. We’ll cover the regression specific material, but those ideas underlie much of regression. Again, I wouldn’t stress about this at this point, but a very quick skim could help get the dust off your recall of this material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Many former students have had some anxiety coming into the class about the learning curve to learn &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;. I am fully anticipating – and can empathize with! – this nervousness. We will talk plenty about how to get going with &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; for those in the class who haven’t used it before, with additional resources as we get going. We’ll cover what you need in class, but if you want to do some extra practice in the first few weeks of the semester while things are (generally) quiet, it might be useful to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Problem set 2</title>
      <link>/assignment/02-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/02-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#required&#34;&gt;Required&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#template-.rmd-file&#34;&gt;Template &lt;code&gt;.RMd&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#submit-on-moodle&#34;&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;required&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Required&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions 2.15, 2.18, and 2.25 (2nd Edition) or 2.13, 2.16, and 2.17 (1st Edition)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skip 2.25 / 2.17 A&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2.25 / 2.17 D, refer to 2.18 / 2.16 A instead of 2.25 / 2.17 A&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;template-.rmd-file&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Template &lt;code&gt;.RMd&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a template RMarkdown file for these questions &lt;a href=&#34;http://sds291.netlify.com/HW/SDS291_HW2_Template.Rmd&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; The link will download the &lt;code&gt;.RMd&lt;/code&gt; template file, which you can upload to the server as we did in class or open in the desktop version of RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are expected to knit to pdf. Please allow enough time to resolve any errors before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submit-on-moodle&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the Homework 1 submission on Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Problem set 3</title>
      <link>/assignment/03-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/03-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#required&#34;&gt;Required&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#for-3.17&#34;&gt;For 3.17:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#for-3.22&#34;&gt;For 3.22:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#additional-question&#34;&gt;Additional Question:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#a.-fit-the-simple-linear-regression-model-of-price2014-on-distance.-interpret-the-relationship-between-price2014-and-distance-in-the-context-of-this-problem.&#34;&gt;a. Fit the simple linear regression model of &lt;em&gt;Price2014&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;em&gt;distance&lt;/em&gt;. Interpret the relationship between &lt;em&gt;Price2014&lt;/em&gt; and distance in the context of this problem.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#b.-next-fit-a-multiple-linear-regression-model-with-distance-and-bedrooms.-how-has-the-addition-of-bedrooms-changed-our-estimate-of-the-relationship-of-distance-to-price2014-use-both-the-estimated-coefficients-and-adjusted-r2-in-your-answer.&#34;&gt;b. Next fit a multiple linear regression model with &lt;em&gt;Distance&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bedrooms&lt;/em&gt;. How has the addition of bedrooms changed our estimate of the relationship of distance to &lt;em&gt;Price2014&lt;/em&gt;? Use both the estimated coefficients and Adjusted &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(R^2\)&lt;/span&gt; in your answer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#c.-find-the-95-confidence-interval-for-the-distance-coefficent-from-the-model-in-b-and-interpret-it-in-the-context-of-this-problem.&#34;&gt;c. Find the 95% Confidence Interval for the distance coefficent from the model in “b” and interpret it in the context of this problem.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#d.-estimate-the-expected-value-of-two-houses-each-0.75-miles-from-the-trail-one-with-3-and-one-with-4-bedrooms.-interpret-this-value-in-a-sentence.&#34;&gt;d. Estimate the expected value of two houses, each 0.75 miles from the trail, one with 3 and one with 4 bedrooms. Interpret this value in a sentence.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#e.-estimate-the-expected-value-of-two-houses-each-with-2-bedrooms-one-thats-0.25-miles-and-another-thats-1.25-miles-from-the-rail-trail.-interpret-this-value-in-a-sentence.&#34;&gt;e. Estimate the expected value of two houses, each with 2 bedrooms, one that’s 0.25 miles and another that’s 1.25 miles from the rail trail. Interpret this value in a sentence.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#submit-on-moodle&#34;&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;required&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Required&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions 3.17, 3.22 (2nd Edition) / 3.11 and 3.15 (1st Edition) - and one more question below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;for-3.17&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For 3.17:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do not use &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; for this problem to fit the regression model or to automatically do the calculations. Use the numbers from the output material in the book.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;B. Calculate a 95% CI where &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(t^*\)&lt;/span&gt; is 1.96. Do not calculate a 90% CI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;for-3.22&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For 3.22:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do as stated in the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;additional-question&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Question:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re using the same data as from class this week: a sample of 104 homes in Northampton, MA to see whether being close to the bike trail enhances the value of the home. Specifically, we’re looking at the association between square feet (a house’s size) and distance from the rail trail with the house’s estimated value in 2014. The variables we’re using are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Price2014&lt;/code&gt;: Zillow price estimate from 2014 (in thousands of dollars)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Distance&lt;/code&gt;: Distance (in &lt;em&gt;miles&lt;/em&gt;) to the nearest entry point to the rail trail network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bedrooms&lt;/code&gt;: Number of bedrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;a.-fit-the-simple-linear-regression-model-of-price2014-on-distance.-interpret-the-relationship-between-price2014-and-distance-in-the-context-of-this-problem.&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;a. Fit the simple linear regression model of &lt;em&gt;Price2014&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;em&gt;distance&lt;/em&gt;. Interpret the relationship between &lt;em&gt;Price2014&lt;/em&gt; and distance in the context of this problem.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;b.-next-fit-a-multiple-linear-regression-model-with-distance-and-bedrooms.-how-has-the-addition-of-bedrooms-changed-our-estimate-of-the-relationship-of-distance-to-price2014-use-both-the-estimated-coefficients-and-adjusted-r2-in-your-answer.&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;b. Next fit a multiple linear regression model with &lt;em&gt;Distance&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bedrooms&lt;/em&gt;. How has the addition of bedrooms changed our estimate of the relationship of distance to &lt;em&gt;Price2014&lt;/em&gt;? Use both the estimated coefficients and Adjusted &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(R^2\)&lt;/span&gt; in your answer.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;c.-find-the-95-confidence-interval-for-the-distance-coefficent-from-the-model-in-b-and-interpret-it-in-the-context-of-this-problem.&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;c. Find the 95% Confidence Interval for the distance coefficent from the model in “b” and interpret it in the context of this problem.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;d.-estimate-the-expected-value-of-two-houses-each-0.75-miles-from-the-trail-one-with-3-and-one-with-4-bedrooms.-interpret-this-value-in-a-sentence.&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;d. Estimate the expected value of two houses, each 0.75 miles from the trail, one with 3 and one with 4 bedrooms. Interpret this value in a sentence.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;e.-estimate-the-expected-value-of-two-houses-each-with-2-bedrooms-one-thats-0.25-miles-and-another-thats-1.25-miles-from-the-rail-trail.-interpret-this-value-in-a-sentence.&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;e. Estimate the expected value of two houses, each with 2 bedrooms, one that’s 0.25 miles and another that’s 1.25 miles from the rail trail. Interpret this value in a sentence.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submit-on-moodle&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no template for this assignment. You’re a pro at making your own RMarkdown files now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are expected to knit to pdf. Please allow enough time to resolve any errors before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the Homework 1 submission on Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Problem set 4</title>
      <link>/assignment/04-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/04-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#required&#34;&gt;Required&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#submit-on-moodle&#34;&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;required&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Required&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions 3.32, 3.47, and 4.15* (2nd Edition) or 3.19, 3.32, 4.14* (1st Edition)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*This question is strongly encouraged, but optional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submit-on-moodle&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no template for this assignment. You’re a pro at making your own RMarkdown files now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are expected to knit to pdf. Please allow enough time to resolve any errors before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the Homework 4 submission on Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Problem set 5</title>
      <link>/assignment/05-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/05-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#required&#34;&gt;Required&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#recommended&#34;&gt;Recommended&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#submit-on-moodle&#34;&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;required&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Required&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions 4.10 (except b), 4.22 (2nd Edition) or 4.9 (except b), 4.21 (1st Edition)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For code, see slides from Monday’s class for 4.10 (especially the &lt;code&gt;ls.diag&lt;/code&gt; function) and Wednesday’s class for 4.22; also see the “lab” that we didn’t get to in class for sample code and suggestions. Be sure to notice what packages need to be included from the RMD files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;recommended&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Recommended&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.20 (2nd Ed), 4.19 (1st Edition)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended for additional practice, won’t count for or against your grade. If you do this question, please include it at the end of the required questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submit-on-moodle&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no template for this assignment. You’re a pro at making your own RMarkdown files now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are expected to knit to pdf. Please allow enough time to resolve any errors before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the Homework 5 submission on Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Problem set 6</title>
      <link>/assignment/06-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/06-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#required&#34;&gt;Required&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#log-transformations&#34;&gt;1. Log Transformations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#odds-probabilities-and-odds-ratios&#34;&gt;2. Odds, Probabilities, and Odds Ratios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#recommended&#34;&gt;Recommended&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#submit-on-moodle&#34;&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;required&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Required&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;log-transformations&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Log Transformations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimate the relationship between Number of Hospitals and Doctors within a sample of counties in the dataset called &lt;code&gt;CountyHealth&lt;/code&gt;. (This dataset is from the &lt;code&gt;Stat2Data&lt;/code&gt; package, just like other problems from the book and you can bring it in like the code we’ve used in class or on previous homework problems (e.g., “Cereal”, or “Perch”))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: lower-alpha&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make a scatterplot of the relationship between &lt;code&gt;MDs&lt;/code&gt; as the response and &lt;code&gt;Hospitals&lt;/code&gt; as the explanatory variable and comment on what you see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make a new variable of the log of MDs and make a scatterplot of the relationship between logged version of &lt;code&gt;MDs&lt;/code&gt; and Hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fit the regression model of the relationship of the logged version of MDs and Hospitals and interpret the slope in a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the regression model from “c” to predict the number of doctors (not log(MDs)) for 4 counties: one with 2,3,9, and 10 hospitals, respectively. Comment on how the difference in predicted number of doctors between the counties with 2 &amp;amp; 3 and 9 &amp;amp; 10 hospitals values corresponds to the regression slope from “c”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;odds-probabilities-and-odds-ratios&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Odds, Probabilities, and Odds Ratios&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are data from an Intensive Care Unit &lt;code&gt;ICU&lt;/code&gt;, on whether someone Survived (Yes/No) and their age group (Youngest: &amp;lt;50yo, Middle: 50-69, Oldest: 70+).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;header&#34;&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;AgeGroup&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Yes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;No&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Youngest&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;54&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Middle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Oldest&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- |         | Yes | No | --&gt;
&lt;!-- |---------|-----|----| --&gt;
&lt;!-- | Youngest |  54 | 5 | --&gt;
&lt;!-- | Middle  |  60 | 17 | --&gt;
&lt;!-- | Oldest  |  46  | 18 | --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: lower-alpha&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Calculate the odds of surviving in the ICU for those in the youngest, middle, and oldest age groups. Interpret the odds of survival for the oldest group in a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the odds in “a”, calculate the probability of survival for each age group. Interpret the probability of survival for the youngest group in a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the table above, calculate the &lt;em&gt;proportion&lt;/em&gt; of the youngest group who survived and compare this answer to your answer in “b”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Calculate a ratio of the odds of survival between those who are Middle vs. Youngest, and a ratio for those Oldest vs. Middle Aged. (No need to interpret, just calculate).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;recommended&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Recommended&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q1e. Does this model actually fit the data well? Try other transformations - of Hospitals, MDs, or both - until you find an arrangement that looks reasonable for a linear regression model; report the results of that model and explain why you think it might be best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submit-on-moodle&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Submit on Moodle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no template for this assignment. You’re a pro at making your own RMarkdown files now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are expected to knit to pdf. Please allow enough time to resolve any errors before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the Homework 6 submission on Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiz 4</title>
      <link>/assignment/04-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/04-quiz/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiz 4 will be open as of Friday 2/28/20 at 12:00pm (noon) and due before noon on Monday 3/2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-question-circle&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; See Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiz 3</title>
      <link>/assignment/03-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/03-quiz/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiz 4 will be open as of Friday 2/28/20 at 12:00pm (noon) and due before noon on Monday 3/2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-question-circle&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; See Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiz 1</title>
      <link>/assignment/01-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/01-quiz/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-question-circle&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; See Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiz 2</title>
      <link>/assignment/02-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/assignment/02-quiz/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiz 2 will be open as of Friday 2/7/20 at 12:00pm (noon) and due before noon on Monday 2/10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-question-circle&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; See Moodle for &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36873&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://moodle.smith.edu/course/view.php?id=36874&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
